A Finding Aid to the Alexander Archipenko Papers, 1904-1986, bulk 1930-1964, in the Archives of American Art AAA.archalex
Archives of American Art
- Financial Records, 1923-1971; Series 6; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  - Paid Bills, 1935-1971; 6.2
    - Medical, 1940-1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1971 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Office Supplies and Equipment, 1954-1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Photography, 1954-1964 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Postage, 1949-1962 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Rent, 1954-1964 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Shipping and Storage, 1935-1970 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Telephone, 1954-1971 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Travel, 1954-1964 (Box 10, Folder 17-19)
    - Typing and Translations, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Utilities, 1954-1970 (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1929-1970; 6.3
    - Bedford Street Expenses, 1961-1970 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Payroll, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Price Lists for Archipenko's Art, 1936-1964 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Price Lists for Archipenko's Art, 1966-1970 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Royalties Paid by Museum of Modern Art for Woman Combing Her Hair, 1953-1968 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Sales Records (Art), 1929-1964 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Tax Returns, Receipts, and Notices, 1929-1964 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Tax Withholding Statements and Interest Statements, 1953-1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Scrapbooks, 1910-1961; Series 7; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 22-25
  Nine volumes, in rough chronological order, contain clippings (including some in Russian, German, Czech, and Japanese), exhibition announcements and catalogs, lecture notices, advertisements and brochures of the Archipenko Art School.
  Also included are a small number of photographs and miscellaneous items. Of particular interest are: (No. 4) U.S. Patent Office brochure for patent 1,626,496 issued to Alexander Archipenko for his Method of Decorating Changeable Display Apparatus, April 26, 1927; (No. 5) photographs of Archipenko's 1927 Tokyo exhibition; (No. 6) installation photographs of exhibitions in Dresden (1921), Leipzig and Berlin (1922), Praha (1923), New York (1928), Chicago (1929), Santa Barbara and San Francisco (1931); also, Archipenko with students at Mills College (1933), and at Chicago Worlds Fair dinner (1933); (No. 7) bibliography (circa 1936), and Archipenko's hand prints; (No. 8) photographs of Moses and Archipenko at work on the sculpture; (No. 9) Golden Gate International Exposition certificate of appreciation; Archie Pen Co., Societe Anonyme, Inc., 1921; and Archipenko's "Message to the Artists for Victory," with letters received in response (1943).
  A large number of printed items in the scrapbooks are also duplicated in Series 8: Printed Matter. "Magazines, Periodicals" (No. 3), contains the following items: Life, March 1, 1948; Arts and Architecture, July 1951; Norte Revista Continental, Octubre 1942; Antiques, June 1952; and Horizons: Ukrainian Monthly of Literature, Arts, amd Critics, May 1951 (in Ukrainian). An additional scrapbook concerning the Archipenko School of Art is a part of Series 5: Teaching.
  - No. 1: "Archipenko", 1910-1927 (Box 22)
  - No. 2, 1912-1923 (Box 22)
  - No. 3: "Magazines, Periodicals", 1942-1952 (Box 22)
  - No. 4, 1927-1961 (Box 23)
  - No. 5, 1919-1930 (Box 24)
  - No. 6, 1921-1934 (Box 23)
  - No. 7: 1919-1938 (Box 25)
  - No. 8: Moses, 1939 (Box 25)
  - No. 9, 1937-1943 (Box 25)
- Printed Material, 1913-1987; Series 8; 3.7 Linear feet Boxes 11-14, 26, OV 29
  Among the "Clippings About/Mentioning Archipenko, or Containing Reproductions" are feature articles, reviews, school advertisements, and obituaries from newspapers and magazines. "Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, etc." are for solo exhibitions and group shows and may include such items as press releases, invitations to openings, posters, and broadsides. A small number of catalogs are from shows where Archipenko served as a juror; also, included are exhibition catalogs of other artists, many of them Archipenko's former students. Among the miscellaneous items of particular interest is an undated brochure describing the Multiplex Advertising Machine, a device similar to the Archipentura, an "apparatus for displaying Changeable Pictures" invented by Archipenko circa 1924 and patented in 1927.
  Additional printed matter, much of which duplicates items filed with this series, can be found in Series 5: Teaching, and Series 7: Scrapbooks.
  8.1: Clippings, 1920-1976
  8.2: Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, etc., 1913-1987
  8.3: Miscellaneous Items, 1918-1970
  - Clippings, 1920-1976; 8.1
    - About/Mentioning Archipenko, or Containing Reproductions, 1913-1950 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - About/Mentioning Archipenko, or Containing Reproductions, 1951-1960 (Box 11, Folder 6-10)
    - About/Mentioning Archipenko, or Containing Reproductions, 1961-1969 (Box 11, Folder 11-15)
    - About/Mentioning Archipenko, or Containing Reproductions, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 16-19)
    - About/Mentioning Archipenko, or Containing Reproductions, 1972-1976 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
      Oversized material housed in Box 26.
    - Miscellaneous Art-Related Topics, 1944-1964 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Oversized Clippings from Box 11, Folder 21, circa 1925-1974 (Box 26)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, etc., 1913-1987; 8.2
    - Solo Exhibitions, 1913-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Solo Exhibitions, 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
      Oversized poster housed in OV 29.
    - Solo Exhibitions, 1970-1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Solo Exhibitions, circa 1918-1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Group Exhibitions, 1913-1944 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Group Exhibitions, 1946-1953 (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
    - Group Exhibitions, 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 12-16)
    - Group Exhibitions, 1960-1962 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Group Exhibitions, 1963-1970 (Box 13, Folder 3-5)
      Oversized catalog housed in Box 26.
    - Group Exhibitions, circa 1935-1965 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Archipenko on Jury, 1926-1963 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Students of Archipenko, 1934-1960 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Other Artists (Survage), 1961 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Oversized Catalog from Box 13, Folder 4, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Oversized Posters from Box 12, Folder 3 and 16, 1959-1960 (Box OV 29)
  - Miscellaneous Items, 1918-1970; 8.3
    - Advertisements and Catalogs for Artists' Services and Tools, circa 1930-1960 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1948-1970 (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - Book, Film, and Periodical Advertisements, Order Forms, and Prospectuses, 1938-1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Bookplate, circa 1930-1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Books About/Mentioning Archipenko, 1922-1923 (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
    - Books About/Mentioning Archipenko, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Books About/Mentioning Archipenko, 1934-1946 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Brochure about Multiplex Advertising Machine (similar to Archipentura), circa 1930-1960 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Catalogs of Museum Collections Containing Works by Archipenko, 1942-1958 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Catalogs of Museum Collections Containing Works by Archipenko, 1968-1970, undated (Box 13, Folder 21-22)
    - Catalogs of Reproductions, Prints, and Slides, circa 1948-1963, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Color Separation Proofs of Works by Archipenko, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
      5 sets; used in unknown publication.
    - Exhibition Entry Forms, 1948, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Gallery Ads Featuring Archipenko, 1958-1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Lecture Announcements, 1930-1956 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Museum Publications Mentioning Archipenko Acquisitions, 1948-1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Poems about Archipenko's Work, 1914-1918, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Postcards (blank), circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Publications of Ukrainian Free Academy of Sciences and Others (in Ukrainian), 1935 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Publications Inscribed to/Annotated by Archipenko, 1934-1953 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Publications Inscribed to/Annotated by Archipenko, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Reproductions of Works by Archipenko, 1923-1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Oversized reproductions housed in Box 26.
    - Reproductions of Interior Views, Annotated to Indicate Rooms Occupied in Aug. 1923 by the Archipenkos, circa 1923-1960 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Oversize Reproductions of Works by Archipenko from Box 14, Folder 10, circa 1923-1960 (Box 26)
    - Oversize Reproductions of Interior Views, Annotated to Indicate Rooms Occupied in Aug. 1923 by the Archipenkos from Box 14, Folder 11, circa 1923-1960 (Box 26)
- Miscellaneous, 1916-1966; Series 9; 0.4 Linear feet Box 14, 16
  Miscellaneous materials include designs, diagrams, unidentified floor plans, recipes, and 3 dry point and 8 printing plates. There is also one film reel (3 in.) of footage from an Archipenko exhibition in Darmstadt.
  - Bases for Sculpture and Base Templates, circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Calendars (unannotated), 1926, 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Diagrams (includes plans for carving stands), circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Dry Point Plates by Archipenko, ( Kneeling, Bending, Angelica), 1916-1922 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition in Darmstadt, circa 1955-1956; 1 Film reels (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Floor Plans, Unidentified, circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - German Currency, circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Headstone Design for Eugen Archypenko (1884-1959), circa 1959 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Poem by Rabindranath Tagore, U. Rittau, Calligrapher, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Bound volume.
  - Printing Plates for Black and White Images (Box 16)
    - Text in the Hand of Archipenko, circa 1930-1960 (Box 16)
    - Gondoliere, circa 1930-1960 (Box 16)
  - Printing Plates for Color Separations (Box 16)
    - Woman with Fan, circa 1930-1960 (Box 16)
    - Unidentified Sculpto-Paintings (three), circa 1930-1960 (Box 16)
    - Unidentified Sculptures (two), circa 1930-1960 (Box 16)
  - Recipes, circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Works of Art by Others (Helen Sewell and unknown), circa 1930-1960 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Photographic Material, 1904-1964; Series 10; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 14-15, 17-21, 26-27
  Studio and informal portraits of Alexander and Angelica Archipenko are by Frans Fiedlin, A. Elnain, Helen Balfour-Morrison, Cy Harriman, Gus Shroeder, A. Luckwin, Lary Colwell, Li Osborne, H. Tarr, and unknown photographers. They include a portrait of Angelica as a young girl, a contemporary copy print of Angelica with her father and sister, circa 1904, and several studio portraits made in Germany. Other people pictured include friends and possibly relatives, the majority of whom are unidentified; also, Frances Gray Archipenko, the second wife.
  Nine photograph albums, 1925-1953, mainly document travel. Vol. 1, May-Nov. 1925, includes photographs and scenic post cards of Niagara Falls, Iowa, Colorado, New Mexico, and Canada; other subjects are friends (many identified), cowboys, Indians, cattle branding, landscapes, camping, and horses. Vol. 2, Aug.-Sept. 1925, contains photographs of a camping trip in Canada, with views of the landscape, friends (many identified), and activities; also included are pictures taken in Chicago, Los Angeles, and Arizona. Photographs of interest in vol. 3, 1925-1953, are Archipenko's first car, 1925; friends (many identified); Woodstock construction, 1930s; studio, kiln, and metal casting facilities, 1940s; Archipenko working with lucite, 1946; fire at Woodstock cottage, 1953; and two self-portraits painted by Angelica. Vol. 4, 1930s mainly records a trip to Bali and includes photographs of Walter Spies; also included are views aboard the Derffling, Suez Canal, Ceylon, Java, China, Japan, Philippines, Hawaii, California, and Archipenko at Mills College. Vol. 5, 1938-1941, consists of photographs taken in Mexico, mainly of San Miguel Allende and the Escuela Universitaria de Bellas Artes where Angelica Archipenko taught sculpture; included are views of classes, faculty, students and student work; also, views of Taxco, Mexico City, and Morelia. A fair number of photographs from the albums were duplicated for various purposes over the years, and these copies are now filed with the appropriate subseries.
  There are a large number of slides, transparencies, negatives, and 86 lantern slides, and 80 glass plates. There may be prints of the vast majority of the negatives, though there are not negatives for every photograph in the collection. Most likely, the black and white lantern slides of ancient art, ethnographic objects, and biological and other specimens were used to illustrate a lecture or may have been collected as possible illustrations for a book.
  Other photographs can be found with Series 4: Writings, which includes a few photographs collected as research notes or intended as illustrations; Series 5: Teaching, includes a scrapbook of the Archipenko Art School that contains pictures of students, and classes and facilities at Woodstock; and Series 7: Scrapbooks, with photographs of exhibition installations, and groups of people including students at Mills College.
  The series is arranged as 9 subseries. Lantern slides and glass plates are housed separately with original folder divisions denoted by dividers; these materials are closed to researchers.
  11.1: People, 1904-1964
  11.2: Places/Travel, circa 1930-1962
  11.3: Works of Art, 1924-1964
  11.4: Exhibitions, 1951-1967
  11.5: Events, circa 1930-1959
  11.6: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1920-1965
  11.7: Photograph Albums, 1925-1963
  11.8: Slides and Transparencies, circa 1950-1960
  11.9: Negatives, circa 1920-1960
  - People, 1904-1964; 10.1
    - Alexander Archipenko (Box 14)
      - Portraits, 1920-1960 (Box 14, Folder 23-26)
      - Informal Views, circa 1925-1964 (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - Close-up View of Archipenko's Hands, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Alexander Archipenko with Others (Box 14)
      - With Angelica, 1920-1950 (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - With Frances, 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      - With Friends, Students, and Colleagues (includes camping trips), circa 1925-1964 (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - With Friends, Carmel, Calif., 1951 (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - With Juries (Columbus, Ohio and unidentified), 1962 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - With Students, University of British Columbia, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Angelica Archipenko (Box 14)
      - Portraits, circa 1910-1930 (Box 14, Folder 35-37)
      - Informal Views (includes portrait in casket), 1920-1957 (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - Angelica Archipenko with Others, 1904-1950 (Box 14, Folder 39)
        Includes 1904 portrait with father and sister.
      - With Sculpture Class, Escuela Universitaria de Bellas Artes, San Miguel Allende, Mexico, circa 1940 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Frances Gray Archipenko, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Groups, Identified (Wozniak family, Barry Miller and mother, Joseph Hirthfisher and mother), 1954-1955 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Groups, Unidentified (includes students at Woodstock), 1922-1964 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Individuals, Identified (Elsa Basilicis; Bette Davis [inscribed to Angelica ]; Walter Spies; friends, students, and babies), 1927-1950 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Individuals, Unidentified, circa 1921-1956 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Nude Models, circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Photographs of Alexander Archipenko from Box 14, Folder 23, 1920-1937 (Box 26)
    - Oversized Photographs of Angelica Archipenko from Box 14, Folder 35, 1920-1929 (Box 26)
    - Oversized Photographs of Unidentified Groups from Box 15, Folder 2, circa 1920 (Box 26)
  - Places/Travel, circa 1930-1962; 10.2
    - Bali (Box 15)
      - Art and Architecture, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Landscapes, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - People, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Shipboard, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Bali and Sumatra (Box 15)
      - Animals, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Art and Architecture, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Landscapes, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - People, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Java, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Mexico (mainly San Miguel de Allende and Escuela de Bellas Artes) (Box 15)
      - Art and Architecture, circa 1936-1942 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Landscapes, circa 1936-1942 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - People, circa 1936-1942 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      - Angelica Archipenko's Grave with Memorial Statue by Alexander Archipenko, Woodlawn Cemetery, New York, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Exteriors, Unidentified, circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Interior, Home of Walter Dupony, Caracas, Venezuela, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Interiors, Unidentified (many may be Woodstock, N.Y.), circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Landscapes, Unidentified (many may be Woodstock, N.Y.), circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Sumatra (Box 15)
      - Animals, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - People, 1930-1939 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Woodstock, N.Y. (Box 15)
      - Home, Exterior, 1949-1965 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Home, Interior, circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - Studio, Exterior, circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - Studio, Interior, circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - Unidentified Buildings, circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Works of Art, 1924-1964; 10.3
    - By Archipenko, Archipentura, circa 1927 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - By Archipenko (Box 15)
      - Prints, Drawings, and Paintings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - Sculpture (includes reproductions from Les Soirées de Paris, 15 Juin 1914), circa 1915-1960 (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - Window Displays, Saks Fifth Avenue, New York, circa 1925 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - By Angelica Archipenko [Gela Forster] (Box 15)
      - Paintings, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - Sculpture, 1938-1951 (Box 15, Folder 35-36)
        Folder 36 contains duplicate photographs.
    - By Other Artists (Box 15)
      - Leon Katz, Madame Aleksandr Archipenko, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 37)
      - Sculpture, circa 1940-1960 (Box 15, Folder 38)
      - Students' Ceramics, Arko Studio, A-Z and unidentified, circa 1929 (Box 15, Folder 39)
      - Students' Paintings, A-Z and unidentified, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 40)
      - Students' Sculpture, 1930-1931, A-Z and unidentified, circa 1940-1960 (Box 15, Folder 41)
      - Students' Sculpture, University of Delaware, Lois M. Detjen, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 42)
      - Students' Sculpture, University of Washington, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 43)
      - Miscellaneous Art and Architecture (includes Egyptian, Greco Roman, and ethnographic objects; probably for lectures), circa 1940-1960 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Oversize Photographs of Sculpture by Archipenko from Box 15, Folder 32, circa 1915-1960 (Box 26)
  - Exhibitions, 1951-1967; 10.4
    - Installations (Box 15)
      - Finch College, Les formes vivantes, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 45)
      - Fondazione Pagani Museo d'Arte Moderna, Legnano, Italy, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 46)
      - Grosshennig Galerie, Dusseldorf, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 47)
      - Miscellaneous Exhibitions, Not Archipenko (IBM-Firmenstil, USIS Bon; unidentified exhibition), circa 1930-1960 (Box 15, Folder 48)
      - Unidentified Location (Germany?), 1960-1969 (Box 15, Folder 49)
      - University of Oregon, Student Exhibition, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 50)
      - University of Washington, Student Exhibition, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Openings (Box 15)
      - Caracas, Venezuela, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 52)
      - Ente Premi Roma, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 53)
      - Galerie Im Erker, St. Gallen, Switzerland, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 54)
      - Germany (Munich and Other Locations), 1960 (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Events, circa 1930-1959; 10.5
    - Archipenko Producing Lithographs at Im Erker Press, St. Gallen, Switzerland, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - Dedication of Angelica Archipenko's Memorial Statue, Woodlawn Cemetery, N.Y., 1959 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - Funeral of Archipenko's Mother, circa 1930 (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1920-1965; 10.6
    - Animals, undated (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - Automobile, 1920s (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - Book Cover, circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Caricatures of Archipenko and his Work, 1911-1937, undated (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - Illustrations for Archipenko: Fifty Creative Years, 1908-1958, circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - Kiln, circa 1940-1960 (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - Plaque, "To the Sixth Sense", undated (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Sculpture Base, "Archipenko © 1948," University of British Columbia, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 66)
  - Photograph Albums, 1925-1963; 10.7
    - Volume 1 (small black album), 1925 (Box 27)
    - Volume 2 (small brown album), 1925 (Box 27)
    - Volume 3 (tan cloth with leather trim), 1925-1953 (Box 27)
    - Volume 4 (embroidered cover), 1930-1939 (Box 27)
    - Volume 5 (wooden cover painted with Mexican scene), 1938-1941 (Box 27)
  - Slides and Transparencies, circa 1950-1960; 10.8
    - 35-mm Color Slides (Box 15)
      - People (include Alexander Archipenko and Angelica Archipenko), circa 1950, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 67)
      - Works of Art by Archipenko and Others from the Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation Museum of Non-Objective Painting (slides), circa 1950-1960 (Box 17)
      - Works of Art by Archipenko and Others from the Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation Museum of Non-Objective Painting, circa 1950-1960 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        List of slide box contents.
      - Zeiss Instrument, circa 1950-1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Color Transparencies used in Archipenko: Fifty Creative Years, 1908-1958, circa 1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Lantern Slides of Early Art and Ethnographic Objects, Biological and Other Specimens, circa 1910-1940; 55 Lantern slides (Box 19)
      Many cracked.
    - Lantern Slides (black and white) (Box 20)
      - Works of Art by Archipenko, circa 1910-1940; 31 Lantern slides; 5 glass slides (Box 20)
      - Plaque, "To the Sixth Sense", circa 1910-1940; 1 glass slides (Box 20)
  - Negatives, circa 1920-1960; 10.9
    - Film Negatives, 10.9.1
      Film negatives of Mexico are mainly of San Migeul de Allende and Escuela de Bellas Artes; art and architecture, landscapes, and people; and copy negatives of many items in photograph album, vol. 5.
      - People (Box 18)
        - Alexander Archipenko, circa 1920-1960 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        - Alexander and Angelica Archipenko, 1950-1959 (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - Alexander Archipenko with Others, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - Angelica Archipenko, circa 1920-1959 (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Individuals, Unidentified, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Places/Travel (Box 18)
        - Angelica Archipenko's Grave with Memorial Statue by Alexander Archipenko, Woodlawn Cemetery, New York, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - Bali, 1930-1939 (Box 18, Folder 10)
        - Interiors, Unidentified, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 11)
        - Mexico, 1938-1941 (Box 18, Folder 12)
        - Woodstock, N.Y., Buildings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Works of Art by Alexander Archipenko (Box 18)
        - Archipentura, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 14)
        - Prints, Drawings, and Paintings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 15)
        - Sculpture, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 16)
        - Window Displays, Saks Fifth Avenue, New York, circa 1925 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Works of Art by Angelica Archipenko [Gela Forster], circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Exhibition (unidentified; with related travel views), circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects (Box 18)
        - Advertisement, Kovler Gallery, Chicago, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 20)